<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Walter Pinson</title>
  <subtitle>Business. Technology. Strategy.</subtitle>
  <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="http://walterpinson.com/"/>
  <updated>2017-06-24T06:32:24.000Z</updated>
  <id>http://walterpinson.com/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>Walter Pinson</name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="http://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Bitcoin Movie Review</title>
    <link href="http://walterpinson.com/Bitcoin-Movie-Review/"/>
    <id>http://walterpinson.com/Bitcoin-Movie-Review/</id>
    <published>2017-06-24T03:29:54.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-06-24T06:32:24.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I’ve been watching a number of Bitcoin documentaries and movies as of late.  I figured that since I was investing the time to watch the movies, I may as well provide a review.  As I complete each review, you’ll be able to navigate to them by clicking “My Take” in the table below.</p>
<p>Interestingly enough, Netflix does not (as of June 2017) have a single Bitcoin title available.  On the other hand, Amazon Prime Video has at least 11 documentaries and one feature film on the topic.</p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th style="text-align:center">Rank</th>
<th style="text-align:left">Name</th>
<th style="text-align:left">My Take</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:center">1</td>
<td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/video/detail/B01MTQZOCV" target="_blank" rel="external">Banking on Bitcoin</a></td>
<td style="text-align:left">Shrem is a stoner; hands caught in cookie jar</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:center">2</td>
<td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/video/detail/B013HU3WX6" target="_blank" rel="external">Bitcoin: The End Of Money As We Know It</a></td>
<td style="text-align:left">First-movers go to jail</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:center">3</td>
<td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Rise-Bitcoin-Daniel-Mross/dp/B00OGM2ZY2" target="_blank" rel="external">The Rise and Rise of Bitcoin</a></td>
<td style="text-align:left">Don’t be fooled by temporary profit-taking</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:center">4</td>
<td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Magic-Money-Tim-Delmastro/dp/B01MU1K517" target="_blank" rel="external">Magic Money: The Bitcoin Revolution</a></td>
<td style="text-align:left">We are unsecured creditors to our banks</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;I’ve been watching a number of Bitcoin documentaries and movies as of late.  I figured that since I was investing the time to watch the m
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Blockchain" scheme="http://walterpinson.com/categories/Blockchain/"/>
    
    
      <category term="bitcoin" scheme="http://walterpinson.com/tags/bitcoin/"/>
    
      <category term="blockchain" scheme="http://walterpinson.com/tags/blockchain/"/>
    
      <category term="payments" scheme="http://walterpinson.com/tags/payments/"/>
    
      <category term="movies" scheme="http://walterpinson.com/tags/movies/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>One In Twenty; A Founder’s Story</title>
    <link href="http://walterpinson.com/One-In-Twenty-A-Founder%E2%80%99s-Story/"/>
    <id>http://walterpinson.com/One-In-Twenty-A-Founder’s-Story/</id>
    <published>2016-04-19T10:00:53.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-06-22T09:37:31.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.ftc.gov/reports/section-319-fair-accurate-credit-transactions-act-2003-fifth-interim-federal-trade" target="_blank" rel="external"><span style="font-weight:400;">One in twenty Americans have errors on their credit report so significant that the errors result in less favorable loan terms or outright rejection</span></a><span style="font-weight:400;">.  From 2002 to 2005, I was one in twenty.  My experience with a particular business was such that they were not dealing with me fairly.  I owed them nothing but they placed a negative tradeline on my credit report. Pressed for time, I gave them money that I did not owe in order to bring the tradeline to close. My credit report, however, never reflected the payoff.  I found myself in need of a service that did not exist; a service that gave me the power to ensure that my credit report tradelines reflected my payments.  And having no other recourse,  I set about creating Alekto.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight:400;">It all started when I was in the process of refinancing my house. </span><a href="http://articles.chicagotribune.com/2002-08-16/business/0208160283_1_mortgage-rates-financial-publisher-hsh-associates-keith-gumbinger" target="_blank" rel="external"><span style="font-weight:400;">Mortgage rates were in free fall</span></a><span style="font-weight:400;"> and I stood to save a great deal of money by getting into a lower interest-rate loan. Once my mortgage broker and I had worked out a deal to my liking, he pulled my credit report so that we could begin to execute.  That&#8217;s when things went left.  I was expecting everything to go smoothly, as this was the second home that I had owned and I went through two separate finance events on my first home.  But my broker called me back and told me something that I was not expecting.  He informed me that he could still do the loan but that  I&#8217;d have to buy down a half a point, based on my credit report.  When I asked him what happened, he told me that there was a negative tradeline on my account for $180.  The company reporting the tradeline was the daycare provider in my old neighborhood.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight:400;">First off, I didn&#8217;t owe my former daycare provider any money.  I gave them proper notice that I was leaving and made the final payment.  But when I contacted them to inform them of their bookkeeping mistake, they told me that they had no record of my making the final payment.  It had been over a year since I moved and I no longer had records of any payments to them.  We were at an impasse.  They were not budging and I needed my mortgage refinanced.  So I  paid them the $180 and got them to fax me a letter stating that the account was current.  My mortgage broker used this letter to perform a </span><a href="https://www.nerdwallet.com/blog/finance/rapid-rescoring-pros-and-cons/" target="_blank" rel="external"><span style="font-weight:400;">rapid rescore</span></a><span style="font-weight:400;"> against my credit report.  This resulted in our ability to close the mortgage under the terms upon which we had originally agreed.  I was very happy with this solution.  Even though it cost me $180, the mortgage savings were orders of magnitude greater than this amount.  All was well with the world, or so I thought.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight:400;">Eighteen months later, after interest rates continued to fall, I decided to refinance my mortgage, again.  I contacted the same broker that I had used before and we began the process.  But, after he pulled my credit report, he saw the same negative tradeline that was there before.  He was puzzled, stating that he remembered my having resolved that issue during the last refinance.  He was correct.  But, the tradeline was never updated.  So I called the daycare provider and informed them of their mistake.  I was told, once again, that they had no record of my having ever paid the $180.  Unfortunately, for me, I had misplaced the letter that they had previously given me.  So I ended up paying them another $180 in order to get another letter that enabled me to close on my new loan.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight:400;">Fast-forward another year.  When I refinanced a third time the $180 tradeline was still showing up on my credit report as not paid.  Luckily, I saved the previous payment letter and did not have to pay a new ransom in order to close my loan.  But I was very upset about what was happening. Clearly, a pattern was revealing itself.  Though required by law to do so, the daycare provider was not updating the credit report tradeline that they filed on me. And though I could have </span><a href="https://www.ftc.gov/sites/default/files/documents/reports/section-319-fair-and-accurate-credit-transactions-act-2003-fifth-interim-federal-trade-commission/130211factareport.pdf" target="_blank" rel="external"><span style="font-weight:400;">disputed the tradeline</span></a><span style="font-weight:400;">, dispute resolution would take thirty (30) days.  Each time this came up, I needed to close my mortgage <span style="text-decoration:underline;"><em><strong>now</strong></em></span>. There had to be a better way.  And if there wasn&#8217;t, I was determined to make one.</span></p>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ftc.gov/reports/section-319-fair-accurate-credit-transactions-act-2003-fifth-interim-federal-trade&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; 
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Startup Life" scheme="http://walterpinson.com/categories/Startup-Life/"/>
    
    
      <category term="startups" scheme="http://walterpinson.com/tags/startups/"/>
    
      <category term="credit reporting" scheme="http://walterpinson.com/tags/credit-reporting/"/>
    
      <category term="mortgage" scheme="http://walterpinson.com/tags/mortgage/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Late Payers Not Always At Fault</title>
    <link href="http://walterpinson.com/Late-Payers-Not-Always-At-Fault/"/>
    <id>http://walterpinson.com/Late-Payers-Not-Always-At-Fault/</id>
    <published>2016-02-27T02:25:21.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-06-22T09:41:42.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://paypastduebills.files.wordpress.com/2016/02/15016504213_11408f9427_z.jpg?w=768" alt="" title="15016504213_11408f9427_z"></p>
<p><span style="font-weight:400;">The first thing that comes to mind when we learn that someone is late paying their bills is that they are irresponsible.  However, when people pay their bills late in today’s economy, it is often due to circumstances beyond their control.  They could be suffering the impacts of any number of macro- or microeconomic factors such as a weak economic recovery, shifts in the global economy, or an unforeseen medical emergency.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight:400;">Even though the economy is in recovery, there is a great deal of underemployment and many people have been forced into low-paying jobs that don’t meet their pre-recession debt obligations.  Worse yet, <a href="http://www.usnews.com/news/the-report/articles/2015/08/23/the-part-time-economic-recovery" target="_blank" rel="external">many are still unemployed</a>.  The number of part-time workers is up 84% post-recession and the number of low-wage jobs has increased by 2.4 million.  Many people who were unemployed were forced to take jobs that were paying much less than what they used to earn.  This can have a very negative impact on one’s ability to pay bills on time.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight:400;">Additionally, shifts in the global economy can have an outsized impact on local geographic markets and, thus, impact entire communities’ ability to pay their bills on time.  For instance, there has been a recent <a href="http://www.chron.com/business/article/More-Texans-are-late-on-credit-card-bills-car-6836280.php" target="_blank" rel="external">substantial increase in the number of Texans who are late paying their credit cards and car loans</a>.  This is due to the fact that oil is now less than $30 a barrel; which is crushing oil-dependent local economies. Louisiana, North Dakota, Oklahoma, and West Virginia are experiencing a similar impact. This is definitely beyond the control of the people affected by this.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight:400;">Finally, an unforeseen medical emergency is naturally beyond anyone’s control.   It can quickly sap a person’s income requiring them to make choices between paying for much-needed medical care or paying their other bills.  In the wake of the Affordable Care Act, <a href="http://www.cnbc.com/id/100840148" target="_blank" rel="external">high medical bills are still sending people into bankruptcy</a>.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight:400;">So don’t be quick too judge if you learn that someone is slow to pay their bills or unable to pay, altogether.  There is actually a very good chance that they could be dealing with circumstances that are completely beyond their control. </span></p>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://paypastduebills.files.wordpress.com/2016/02/15016504213_11408f9427_z.jpg?w=768&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;15016504213_11408f9427_z&quot;
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Credit Reporting" scheme="http://walterpinson.com/categories/Credit-Reporting/"/>
    
    
      <category term="credit reporting" scheme="http://walterpinson.com/tags/credit-reporting/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>The CFPB Has Been on a Tear...</title>
    <link href="http://walterpinson.com/The-CFPB-Has-Been-on-a-Tear/"/>
    <id>http://walterpinson.com/The-CFPB-Has-Been-on-a-Tear/</id>
    <published>2015-07-24T19:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-06-22T09:59:59.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Those who expected the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau (CFPB), Elizabeth Warren’s brainchild, to be a toothless regulator are either sorely disappointed or thoroughly amused, right now.  The CFPB has been really busy over the last two (2) months (June - July 2015) fighting to protect consumer rights.</p>
<h3 id="“P”-is-for-Protection"><a href="#“P”-is-for-Protection" class="headerlink" title="“P” is for Protection"></a>“P” is for Protection</h3><p>The Consumer Financial Protection Bureau is responsible for protecting the rights of consumers against abuses from the financial industry.  Certain populations have a higher likelihood of being targets of various finance schemes.  As such, it is no coincidence that two (2) of the  companies that the CFPB took action against, during this period, were found to be taking advantage of blacks or military personnel and their families.  Additionally, the CFPB has take action action against companies in the medical billing and collections business.  It is common practice for medical debt collectors to report adverse information to consumers’ credit reports prior to the consumer even knowing that they owe money.  Home owners impacted by the financial crisis, and students are also susceptible to abuses.  The CFPB recently addressed businesses who took advantage of these consumers, as well.</p>
<h3 id="Need-the-Dough"><a href="#Need-the-Dough" class="headerlink" title="Need the Dough"></a>Need the Dough</h3><p>In the last sixty (60) days, alone, the CFPB has sanctioned more than thirteen (13) financial institutions  and it has assessed  nearly one billion dollars ($1B) in fines and compensation for aggrieved consumers.</p>
<p><img src="http://www.abenzymes.com/wp-content/files_mf/cache/th_fda751ccf7f94f62d15e5b3bde725d3b_1314014643iStock_000005460442Large.jpg" alt=""></p>
<p>This flurry of activity is not unique to the last two (2) months.  The CFPB has been very active for the entirety of 2015.  One can only hope that it continues.  It is obviously a saving grace to the consumers who have been directly affected by the surfaced issues.  But, it is equally good medicine for the offending financial institutions.  The CFPB helps them uncover blind spots and the improvements should, ultimately, make these businesses more profitable.</p>
<h3 id="Resources"><a href="#Resources" class="headerlink" title="Resources"></a>Resources</h3><table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th style="text-align:center">#</th>
<th style="text-align:center">Date</th>
<th style="text-align:left">Offending Company</th>
<th style="text-align:right">Consumer Relief</th>
<th style="text-align:right">Civil Penalty</th>
<th style="text-align:right">Total </th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:center">1</td>
<td style="text-align:center">07/23</td>
<td style="text-align:left">Student Financial Services, Inc.</td>
<td style="text-align:right">$5.20M</td>
<td style="text-align:right">$1</td>
<td style="text-align:right">$5.20M </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:center">2</td>
<td style="text-align:center">07/22</td>
<td style="text-align:left">Discover Bank</td>
<td style="text-align:right">$16.00M</td>
<td style="text-align:right">$2.50M</td>
<td style="text-align:right">$18.50M </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:center">3</td>
<td style="text-align:center">07/21</td>
<td style="text-align:left">Citibank</td>
<td style="text-align:right">$700.00M</td>
<td style="text-align:right">$35.00M</td>
<td style="text-align:right">$735.00M</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:center">4</td>
<td style="text-align:center">07/20</td>
<td style="text-align:left">Military allotment abusers</td>
<td style="text-align:right">-</td>
<td style="text-align:right">-</td>
<td style="text-align:right">- </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:center">5</td>
<td style="text-align:center">07/14</td>
<td style="text-align:left">American Honda Finance Corporation</td>
<td style="text-align:right">$24.00M</td>
<td style="text-align:right">-</td>
<td style="text-align:right">$24.00M </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:center">6</td>
<td style="text-align:center">07/01</td>
<td style="text-align:left">Affinion Group Holdings</td>
<td style="text-align:right">$6.80M</td>
<td style="text-align:right">$1.90M</td>
<td style="text-align:right">$8.70M </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:center">7</td>
<td style="text-align:center">07/01</td>
<td style="text-align:left">Intersections</td>
<td style="text-align:right">$0.06M</td>
<td style="text-align:right">$1.20M</td>
<td style="text-align:right">$1.26M </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:center">8</td>
<td style="text-align:center">06/18</td>
<td style="text-align:left">Syndicated Office Systems, LLC dab Central Financial Control</td>
<td style="text-align:right">$5.40M</td>
<td style="text-align:right">$0.50M</td>
<td style="text-align:right">$5.90M </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:center">9</td>
<td style="text-align:center">06/17</td>
<td style="text-align:left">Security Automotive National Acceptance Company, LLC</td>
<td style="text-align:right">-</td>
<td style="text-align:right">-</td>
<td style="text-align:right">- </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:center">10</td>
<td style="text-align:center">06/05</td>
<td style="text-align:left">Guarantee Mortgage Corporation</td>
<td style="text-align:right">-</td>
<td style="text-align:right">$0.23M</td>
<td style="text-align:right">$0.23M </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:center">11</td>
<td style="text-align:center">06/04</td>
<td style="text-align:left">PHH Corporation</td>
<td style="text-align:right">$109.00M</td>
<td style="text-align:right">-</td>
<td style="text-align:right">$109.00M </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:center">12</td>
<td style="text-align:center">06/04</td>
<td style="text-align:left">RPM Mortgage, Inc.</td>
<td style="text-align:right">$18.00M</td>
<td style="text-align:right">$1.00M</td>
<td style="text-align:right">$19.00M </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:center">13</td>
<td style="text-align:center">06/04</td>
<td style="text-align:left">Erwin Robert Hirt, RPM CEO</td>
<td style="text-align:right">-</td>
<td style="text-align:right">$1.00M</td>
<td style="text-align:right">$1.00M </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:center"></td>
<td style="text-align:center"></td>
<td style="text-align:left"><strong>Total</strong></td>
<td style="text-align:right"><strong>$884.75M</strong></td>
<td style="text-align:right"><strong>$43.35M</strong></td>
<td style="text-align:right"><strong>$929.10M</strong> </td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;Those who expected the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau (CFPB), Elizabeth Warren’s brainchild, to be a toothless regulator are either
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Credit Reporting" scheme="http://walterpinson.com/categories/Credit-Reporting/"/>
    
    
      <category term="credit reporting" scheme="http://walterpinson.com/tags/credit-reporting/"/>
    
      <category term="cfpb" scheme="http://walterpinson.com/tags/cfpb/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Rich Piana Saved My Legs</title>
    <link href="http://walterpinson.com/rich-piana-saved-my-legs/"/>
    <id>http://walterpinson.com/rich-piana-saved-my-legs/</id>
    <published>2014-03-16T07:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-06-24T03:23:59.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Why can you find me in the gym nearly every day of the week?  </p>
<p>Like most guys, I want to look good.  On the one hand, I can admit, it is pure vanity.  On the other hand, it really is about being healthy and achieving longevity.  Putting in work now will ensure that I maximize my quality of life in the later years.</p>
<p>This is why I took up bodybuilding, or weight training or whatever you want to call it, in the first place.  Now, don’t get me wrong.  I’m not a professional.  I have no intentions of getting on stage (in a speedo) and competing with anyone.  This is something that I do for me.</p>
<h2 id="Training-Wheels"><a href="#Training-Wheels" class="headerlink" title="Training Wheels"></a>Training Wheels</h2><p>After years of trying to grow my legs yielding only marginal results, one tip from Rich Piana changed everything.</p>
<div style="text-align: center"><br><iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/-EVXC_6-gss" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe><br></div>

<p>Rich delivers two major tips in the Training Wheels video</p>
<ol>
<li>Be sure to squat full range of motion (which I already <a href="http://www.poliquingroup.com/Tips/tabid/130/EntryId/1638/Tip-463-Squat-Training-Tips-To-Use-Range-Of-Motion-To-Your-Advantage.aspx" target="_blank" rel="external">learned from Poliquin</a>)</li>
<li><strong>Don’t rest at the top</strong></li>
</ol>
<p>I’ve ALWAYS rested at the top.  No wonder I wasn’t seeing results that I was looking for.  Heavy squats hurt.  They don’t just hurt your legs, they hurt your <em>soul</em>.  Resting at the top was my way of intermittently relieving the stress on my CNS (central nervous system) to allow me to carry forward with the next rep.  The problem is, the stress on the muscle is actually what is requried to promote growth.  So ultimately, I had been working against myself.</p>
<h2 id="Fighting-Genes"><a href="#Fighting-Genes" class="headerlink" title="Fighting Genes"></a>Fighting Genes</h2><p>Genetically speaking, my parents blessed me with “the gift and the curse” (obligatory <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Blueprint_2:_The_Gift_%26_The_Curse" target="_blank" rel="external">Jay Z reference</a>).  As more of an ectomorph with a super-high metabolism, it is fairly difficult for me to put on weight.  So I am naturally a skinny kid.  This is great if you want to be a runway model.  …not so much, when you are walking up and down South Beach.</p>
<p>Aside from the high metabolism, my genetic makeup seems to be schizophrenic.  My upperbody and glutes seem to be wired for size; which has allowed me to achieve impressive gains in those areas.  My quads, hams, and calfs got the short end of the genetic stick, though.</p>
<p>I’ve tried a number of different things, for years, and was unable to achieve any substantial growth in my legs.  I was becoming fearful that I was forever doomed to have chicken legs.  Now I can see the light at the end of the tunnel.  Thank you, Rich.  …thank you.</p>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;Why can you find me in the gym nearly every day of the week?  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like most guys, I want to look good.  On the one hand, I can admit,
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Do You Even Lift?" scheme="http://walterpinson.com/categories/Do-You-Even-Lift/"/>
    
    
      <category term="bodybuilding" scheme="http://walterpinson.com/tags/bodybuilding/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>TSF is now ...TSF</title>
    <link href="http://walterpinson.com/TSF-is-now-TSF/"/>
    <id>http://walterpinson.com/TSF-is-now-TSF/</id>
    <published>2013-06-06T07:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-06-22T09:43:28.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>At the end of <a href="http://trianglestartupfactory.com/event/spring-2013-pitch-day/" target="_blank" rel="external">TSF Pitch Day Spring 2013</a>, <a href="http://trianglestartupfactory.com/tsf-will-change-the-triangle-forever/" target="_blank" rel="external">Chris Heivly</a> announced that TSF is rebranding and that moving forward it will be know as …wait for it …TSF.  </p>
<p>Amazing, isn’t it?    :-)  </p>
<p>All kidding aside, it is a testament to the evolution of this new accelerator that the Triangle Startup Factory has evolved into <strong><em>THE</em> Startup Factory</strong>.  The acronym still holds, but the accelerator has outgrown it’s geography.</p>
<p>In the Fall 2012 class, one of the five portfolio companies (<a href="http://www.alekto.co" target="_blank" rel="external">Alekto</a>) was from Washington, DC.  In the <a href="http://trianglestartupfactory.com/spring-2013/" target="_blank" rel="external">Spring 2013 class</a>, two of the five portfolio companies were from outside the Triangle.  One was from Washington, DC and the other was from New York.</p>
<p>Chris Heivly explained it well when he said that rebranding by dropping the word, “Triangle”, was a move toward ensuring that TSF attracted the best startups and the best investors from across the country, if not the globe.  But rest assured that TSF isn’t moving anywhere.  It’s going to stay put, right in downtown Durham.</p>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;At the end of &lt;a href=&quot;http://trianglestartupfactory.com/event/spring-2013-pitch-day/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;TSF Pitch Day Sprin
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Startup Life" scheme="http://walterpinson.com/categories/Startup-Life/"/>
    
    
      <category term="startups" scheme="http://walterpinson.com/tags/startups/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Hello World</title>
    <link href="http://walterpinson.com/hello-world/"/>
    <id>http://walterpinson.com/hello-world/</id>
    <published>2013-05-26T07:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-06-24T03:13:56.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3 id="I’m-back"><a href="#I’m-back" class="headerlink" title="I’m back!"></a>I’m back!</h3><p>It took me long enough.  But, I’m finally back from my long hiatus.  It’s not like I don’t have anything to talk about.  I’ve been meaning to start blogging again for the longest time.  I’ve just been super-busy.</p>
<p>Luckily, in the interim, I’ve grown quite fond of git and Github.  So when I came across the article, <a href="http://tom.preston-werner.com/2008/11/17/blogging-like-a-hacker.html" target="_blank" rel="external">“blogging like a hacker”</a> (which should be titled “blogging like a <em>BOSS</em>“), it was all the excuse I needed.  I could kill two birds with one stone.  …tinker a bit.  …and get back into blogging.</p>
<p>So my new blog is powered by <a href="http://jekyllrb.com/" target="_blank" rel="external">jekyll</a>, hosted by <a href="http://github.com" target="_blank" rel="external">GitHub</a>, and I’m writing this post using <a href="http://prose.io/" target="_blank" rel="external">prose</a>.</p>
<p>Tight.</p>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;h3 id=&quot;I’m-back&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#I’m-back&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;I’m back!&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;I’m back!&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;It took me long enough.  But, I’m finally ba
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Do You Even Code?" scheme="http://walterpinson.com/categories/Do-You-Even-Code/"/>
    
    
      <category term="blogging" scheme="http://walterpinson.com/tags/blogging/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>The Importance of Abstraction in Cloud Computing</title>
    <link href="http://walterpinson.com/The-Importance-of-Abstraction-in-Cloud-Computing/"/>
    <id>http://walterpinson.com/The-Importance-of-Abstraction-in-Cloud-Computing/</id>
    <published>2009-12-21T12:30:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-06-22T07:46:07.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My colleague, Peter Palmieri, just penned a blog post about Microsoft’s recent announcement that the Azure platform will offer extensive and familiar relational database features via SQL Data Services (SDS). In his post, Leveraging Skills, Peter discusses the fact that .NET developers will be able to leverage their existing SQL Server database skills when developing against the Azure platform.</p>
<p><a href="http://walterpinson.sys-con.com/node/883998" target="_blank" rel="external">read more</a></p>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;My colleague, Peter Palmieri, just penned a blog post about Microsoft’s recent announcement that the Azure platform will offer extensive 
    
    </summary>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Is Cloud Computing Like Teenage Sex?</title>
    <link href="http://walterpinson.com/Is-Cloud-Computing-Like-Teenage-Sex/"/>
    <id>http://walterpinson.com/Is-Cloud-Computing-Like-Teenage-Sex/</id>
    <published>2009-12-06T05:45:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-06-22T07:46:01.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It was once said back <strong>in the early ‘90s</strong> that “<a href="http://www.allbusiness.com/technology/software-services-applications-network-software/7765382-1.html" title="Client/server computing: release the power of the desktop." target="_blank" rel="external">Client/server computing is a little like teenage sex</a> – everyone talks about it, few actually do it, and even fewer do it right. Nevertheless many people believe client/server computing is the next major step in the evolution of corporate information systems.”</p>
<p>Can the same be said about cloud computing, today?</p>
<p>It is evident that cloud computing is the next major step in computing, in general. But is it the next major step in the evolution of <strong><em>corporate</em></strong> information systems? Everyone is certainly talking about it; but who is actually doing it?</p>
<p><img src="http://res.sys-con.com/story/mar09/862933/Teenage%20Sex_0.jpg" alt=""></p>
<p>According to <a href="http://pewresearch.org/pubs/948/cloud-computing-gains-in-currency" title="Cloud Computing Gains in Currency" target="_blank" rel="external">Pew Research</a>, anyone with a Gmail or YouTube account is participating in the cloud computing revolution. Perhaps I need to change my perspective about cloud computing in order to agree with them. The Pew report focuses on end-user adoption of cloud-based services, or SaaS. The way I see it, end-users don’t engage in cloud-based computing. End-users use applications. Regardless, neither Gmail nor YouTube represent an evolution in <strong><em>corporate</em></strong> information systems.</p>
<p>So again, what corporations are engaged in cloud computing?</p>
<p><a href="http://kevinljackson.blogspot.com/2008/07/correlative-analytics-cloud-computing.html" title="Correlative Analytics:  Cloud Computing Google Mindshare" target="_blank" rel="external">Kevin Jackson</a> and <a href="http://peterlaird.blogspot.com/2008/09/comparing-cloud-computing-mindshare.html" title="Comparing Cloud Computing Mindshare Levels Between the U.S., Europe, and Asia" target="_blank" rel="external">Peter Laird</a> have started some interesting analysis on Cloud Computing mindshare. It is not surprising that, in Kevin’s analysis, the usual suspects show up in the top three (3): Amazon, Google, and Microsoft. But these three represent companies that have made huge infrastructure investments and are figuring out how to gain further returns from those investments. What they don’t represent is the adoption of cloud computing by the managers of <strong><em>corporate</em></strong> information systems.</p>
<p>It seems that information on which companies are adopting cloud computing is hard to come by. For this reason, Peter Laird issues a call to action at the end of his <a href="http://peterlaird.blogspot.com/2008/09/comparing-cloud-computing-mindshare.html" title="Comparing Cloud Computing Mindshare Levels Between the U.S., Europe, and Asia" target="_blank" rel="external">post</a>; “Cloud vendors, what can you say about your customers? Please reveal.”</p>
<p>For now, at least, it looks like cloud vendors don’t kiss and tell. That said, I can’t wait to be enlightened.</p>
<p><a href="http://apache.sys-con.com/node/862933" target="_blank" rel="external">Article originally published on Sys-Con Media</a></p>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;It was once said back &lt;strong&gt;in the early ‘90s&lt;/strong&gt; that “&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.allbusiness.com/technology/software-services-applicati
    
    </summary>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Automated Customer Service: Nike just stole my heart!??!</title>
    <link href="http://walterpinson.com/Automated-Customer-Service-Nike-just-stole-my-heart/"/>
    <id>http://walterpinson.com/Automated-Customer-Service-Nike-just-stole-my-heart/</id>
    <published>2009-10-31T16:41:52.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-06-22T07:45:56.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I can’t believe that I’m writing this.&#160; But I have to give credit where credit is due.&#160; I just called to check on an order that I placed with Nike.com a while ago that hasn’t yet been delivered.&#160; My first reaction to the automated voice response was a negative one.&#160; I hate those things.&#160; Normally, […]</p>
<p><a href="http://walterpinson.sys-con.com/node/1167221" target="_blank" rel="external">read more</a></p>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;I can’t believe that I’m writing this.&amp;#160; But I have to give credit where credit is due.&amp;#160; I just called to check on an order that
    
    </summary>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Code Contracts in .NET Help Distributed Software Development Teams</title>
    <link href="http://walterpinson.com/Code-Contracts-in-NET-Help-Distributed-Software-Development-Teams/"/>
    <id>http://walterpinson.com/Code-Contracts-in-NET-Help-Distributed-Software-Development-Teams/</id>
    <published>2009-06-11T09:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-06-22T07:45:49.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Code Contracts are very useful under any circumstance; however, they are particularly useful in helping distributed software development teams increase team efficiency, improve product quality, and mitigate against risks associated with team dispersion.</p>
<p><a href="http://walterpinson.sys-con.com/node/883999" target="_blank" rel="external">read more</a></p>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;Code Contracts are very useful under any circumstance; however, they are particularly useful in helping distributed software development 
    
    </summary>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Architectural Fidelity with Globally Distributed Software Development Teams</title>
    <link href="http://walterpinson.com/Architectural-Fidelity-with-Globally-Distributed-Software-Development-Teams/"/>
    <id>http://walterpinson.com/Architectural-Fidelity-with-Globally-Distributed-Software-Development-Teams/</id>
    <published>2009-03-19T23:44:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-06-22T07:45:44.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Software businesses that engage in offshore outsourcing face a number of risks.&#160; Of particular importance to the software architect, is the risk associated with the architectural fidelity of the company’s software products.&#160; Small and mid-sized enterprises (SMEs) and ISVs face greater levels of difficulty than do their large enterprise counterparts when it comes to managing […]</p>
<p><a href="http://walterpinson.sys-con.com/node/885658" target="_blank" rel="external">read more</a></p>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;Software businesses that engage in offshore outsourcing face a number of risks.&amp;#160; Of particular importance to the software architect,
    
    </summary>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Hyundai schools us on Relationship Marketing</title>
    <link href="http://walterpinson.com/Hyundai-schools-us-on-Relationship-Marketing/"/>
    <id>http://walterpinson.com/Hyundai-schools-us-on-Relationship-Marketing/</id>
    <published>2009-02-17T08:19:31.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-06-22T07:45:40.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hyundai has produced commercials to create awareness about its new Hyundai Assurance Program.</p>
<p>I don’t watch much television, so the fact that I’ve seen these commercial a few times is indicative of a strong marketing campaign.<br>When visiting its web site, Hyundai let’s you know that “WE’VE GOT YOUR BACK”.&#160; The Hyundai Assurance Program, in a nutshell, […]</p>
<p><a href="http://walterpinson.sys-con.com/node/862934" target="_blank" rel="external">read more</a></p>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;Hyundai has produced commercials to create awareness about its new Hyundai Assurance Program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t watch much television, so th
    
    </summary>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Experian snubs FTC. Who will win this fight?…</title>
    <link href="http://walterpinson.com/Experian-snubs-FTC-Who-will-win-this-fight-%E2%80%A6/"/>
    <id>http://walterpinson.com/Experian-snubs-FTC-Who-will-win-this-fight-…/</id>
    <published>2009-01-25T00:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-06-22T09:59:26.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The FACT Act requires that the FTC improve the accuracy of consumer records and make improvements in the use of, and consumer access to credit information.&#160; It says as much in the first paragraph.<br>The FTC has devised a methodology that requires experts and consumers to work together to audit CRAs for accuracy and completeness.&#160; It […]</p>
<p><a href="http://walterpinson.sys-con.com/node/896788" target="_blank" rel="external">read more</a></p>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;The FACT Act requires that the FTC improve the accuracy of consumer records and make improvements in the use of, and consumer access to c
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Credit Reporting" scheme="http://walterpinson.com/categories/Credit-Reporting/"/>
    
    
      <category term="credit reporting" scheme="http://walterpinson.com/tags/credit-reporting/"/>
    
      <category term="experian" scheme="http://walterpinson.com/tags/experian/"/>
    
      <category term="ftc" scheme="http://walterpinson.com/tags/ftc/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
